（ルーク）あっ。
（ノノハ・キュービック）カイト！
Kaito!
（ソウジ）カイト君！
Kaito...
腕輪を…　捨てた…。
You threw the Armband away...
なぜだ？
なぜ　僕の隣に来ないんだ？
Why? Why won't you come to my side?
（ビショップ）ルーク様。
イヤだ…　イヤだぁ…。
Sir Rook...
No... No... No!
あっ！
イヤだ～！
（３人）うっ。
僕のカイト　僕のカイト～！
Kaito is mine! Kaito is mine!
落ち着いてください　ルーク様！
イヤだ…　イヤだぁ…。
Calm down, Sir Rook!
No... No!
カイト…　カイトは　僕のものなんだ～！
Kaito... Kaito is mine and only mine!
Kaito is mine!
僕のカイト～！
（フンガ）信じられん。
I can't believe this. Is that really the Sir Rook we loved and respected?
あれが　我らの敬愛してきた
ルーク様だというのか。
（メイズ）まるで　おもちゃを取られた
だだっ子。　見るに堪えなかったわ。
It's like a spoiled child who's had his toy taken away.
I couldn't watch it to the end.
（フンガ）残念だが…
もう　これ以上は…。
It's sad, but this must end.
私も…。　ダイスマン。
I agree.
Diceman?
（ダイスマン）えっ？！
（メイズ）あんたは　どうすんの？
What are you going to do?
Um, well... You know... I guess...
いや　僕は　つまり～　　その…
あっ　ギャモンちゃん　君は？
What about you, Gammie?
あれ？
Huh?
（ダイスマン）ギャモンちゃん？
Where'd he go?
（エレナ）あんたのお仲間が配信した
極秘情報と　ルーク様のお宝映像→
Because of the confidential information your friends leaked and Sir Rook's lovely video,
世界中の幹部が見て
大パニックですって…。
the POG leaders all around the world are in panic.
ＰＯＧも　もう終わりね。
これから　どうするつもり？
The POG is done for.
What are you gonna do?
（ギャモン）さあな…。
Dunno.
手伝ってあげてもいいけど。
へっ。
I may be kind enough to help you.
Rook will act. With all his might.
心の声
ルークが動く…
己の全てをかけて。
勝てるか？　カイト。
心の声
Can you win, Kaito?
（ルーク）くっ　カイト…。
Kaito...
kimi no nounai he shinnyuu nemutteiru sukima ni
I infiltrate your brain while you're sleeping.
Baby, open the gate!
fukuzatsu sugi sekyuriti kakusareru to abakitaku naru
The security's too tough, but I want to expose what's hidden.
barabara ni chirabatteiru pasuwado wo hiroi atsume
I gather the pieces of the shattered password.
kakushin ni sematte iku sono shoutai wo misete
I get close to the core. Show me who you really are!
kantan ni kuria dekinai saki nante motto yomenai
I can't clear it easily. I can't even see what lies ahead.
kaidoku fukanou sumairu kikenna pazuru
Your indecipherable smile is a hazardous puzzle.
rokku sareta doa aru nara zutto tataite miru beki kazana hiraku wa
When you see a locked door, you should just hit it until a crack opens.
eien ni hodokenai nazo nanka wa nai
There's no mystery that lasts forever!
makiokosu, it's a supernova
I made it, it's a supernova!
tobikiri shigekitekina hirameki wo agemashou
Let's flash so bright it'd hurt!
Misskey-Misskey La-Tu-Ma
yume no naka it's a supernova
In my dreams, it's a supernova!
watashi wa sou brain diver
Yeah, I'm the brain diver!
kimi ga sagashi motometeru kotae ni nareru made
Until I can find the answer you're looking for...
Brain diver!
Eternal Existence
（ノノハ）未来で見た男の人が？！
（カイト）ああ…。
The person you saw in your premonition...
俺から　ルークに…　変わった。
It changed from me to Rook.
あの未来は
現実になっちまうのか？
Will that future become reality?
ルークの手で…。
あぁ。　ないない！　そんなこと。
Will Rook make it real?
No way! If the conditions change, the future will change too, right?
条件が変われば　未来も
変わるんでしょ？　大丈夫　大丈夫。
It'll be fine!
簡単に言うな　簡単に。
It's not that simple you know.
全く　彼ってば　困った人よね。
He's such a difficult guy. You're his best friend, yet he caused you so much trouble.
親友のカイトを悩ましてさ。
今でもカイトのこと…　好きなくせに。
He still loves you.
カイト　隠さずに
全部話してくれたね。
Thanks for telling me everything. I like that.
いい心がけだわ。
なんだ　そりゃ？
Give me a break.
その調子で　もう一切
隠し事はしないでね。
Keep it up and don't try to hide stuff from me.
そして　私を
置いてきぼりにしない。
Or else just leave me behind.
分かった？　約束よ。
Okay? Promise.
ああ　約束する。
[TEL]
It's a promise.
おっ。
うん。
誰だ？　こんな時間に。
Who would be calling this late?
Hello?
誰だ？　何の用だ？
Who is it? What do you want?
[TEL]（ルーク）いや　カイト…　僕だよ。
Hey, Kaito. It's me.
あっ　ルーク！
あっ。
Rook!
カイト。
Kaito...
カイト～！
Kaito!
はぁ　カイト！　はぁ　はぁ　はぁ。
何なんだよ…　それ…。
The hell is with him?
よかった！
I'm so glad! I was afraid you wouldn't come.
もし来てくれなかったら
どうしようかと思った。
ルーク。　俺に何の用だ？
何をたくらんでる？！
Rook, what do you want from me?
What are you scheming?
アハッ。　嫌だなぁ。
ゆうべ　電話で言ったとおりだよ。
Oh, come on...
It's just what I told you over the phone last night.
ありがとう　カイト。　僕の願いを
あっ。
かなえてくれて。
Thanks for fulfilling my wish.
ねえ　カイト　ごはん食べた？
Say, have you eaten yet?
えっ？！　いや～　まだだけど…。
Um, not yet...
僕も。　おなか　ペコペコさ。
ちょっと待て　ルーク！　おい！
Me neither! I'm starving!
Hey! Wait, Rook! Stop!
Octopus balls
1 pack ¥500
Drinks
（店員）はいよ。
Here you go.
ルーク。
あっ。
Rook!
食えよ。
あっ。
Have some.
ハッ　はふ　はふ　はふ。
いただきます。
Thanks!
ハッ　はふ　はふ　はふい！
気い　つけろ。　口ん中　むけるぞ。
Careful, you'll burn your tongue.
カイト。
ん？！
中から　何か出てきた。
Kaito... There was something inside it.
ああ　たこか。
た　たこ？！　オクトパス？！
You mean the octopus?
What? An octopus?
お前　たこ食うの　初めてか？
うん。　でも　おいしい。
Your first time eating octopus?
Yeah, but it's good.
そっか。　よかった。　ハハッ。
That's great then.
（キュービック）ＧＰＳ　作動正常。
現在カイトは　商店街のたこ焼き屋前。
GPS function — regular.
Kaito is in the shopping district at an octopus ball shop.
３つ目を食べた。
He just ate his third one.
He didn't challenge him to a puzzle battle?
目的は　パズルバトルではないのか？
ルークは　何のために　カイトを？
Then why did Rook ask Kaito to go on a man date?
たこ焼き目当てじゃないのは
確かだね。
I doubt it's for the octopus balls.
ノノハ君から聞いたときは驚いたよ。
まさか…。
I was surprised when Nonoha told me. It was unexpected...
（ノノハ）えっ？！
ルーク君と　２人きりで会う！
Huh? Alone with Rook?!
「一日だけ　昔に…
あの頃に戻ってみたい」。
I want to return to the old times...
even if it's just for a day.
そう言ってた。
なんで　ＯＫしたの？！　危険だよ！
That's what he said.
Why did you agree? It's dangerous!
何かあるに決まってんじゃん！
知りてえんだ。
あっ。
He must be plotting something!
I want to know...
ルークが　何を考えてるのか。
あの未来を変えるために…。
what Rook is thinking.
To change that future.
隠さずに話した。　だから行かせろ。
あっ…。
There, I didn't hide anything. So don't stop me.
Then try to convince him!
だったら　ルーク君を説得してきて！
もう　仲直りしようって。
Make up with him!
ノノハ。
カイトが　親友のカイトが言えば
絶対　心に届くはずだから。
Nonoha...
You're his best friend, so you may be able to reach him!
やってみるよ…。
I'll try.
Wow, so many puzzle mags!
（ルーク）うわ～　すごいや！
パズル雑誌が　こんなに。
ああ。
僕　街なんて　めったに来ないから。
Yeah.
I hardly come to town, you know.
ウハハッ。
う～ん。　悪くないけど
僕だったら…。
Not bad. But if it were me...
あぁ！　こら！
Hey!
（店員）４８０円です。
ルーク　お前なぁ。
It's 480 yen.
Rook, you rascal...
ごめん　つい　夢中になっちゃって。
Sorry, I got carried away.
線路とポイントを使ったら　面白い
パズルが作れるかも。　どうかな　カイト？
Points and lines could turn into an interesting puzzle.
What do you think, Kaito?
あっ　ああ　いいな。
完成したら　やらせろよ。
えへっ。
Yeah, I guess. Let me solve it if you make it.
ポーンをｇの５。
ナイトをｄの４。
Pawn to G5.
Knight to D4.
クイーンをｅの１。　チェック！
あっ　やべえ！
Queen to E1. Check!
Damn!
キング　ｇの２へ撤退。
アハッ　だったら　僕は…。
King retreat to G2.
Then I'll...
いよっ。　うん。　ふ～ん。
（店員）
お待たせいたしました。　お砂糖と
ミルクは　いくつご利用ですか？
Thank you for waiting.
Would you like any milk or sugar?
砂糖　４８本ください。
は　はい。
46 packs of sugar, please.
Y-Yes, sir!
はっ…　お前　本当に
パズルが好きなんだな。
You really love puzzles, don't you?
カイトも　昔は　そうだったじゃない。
You were like that too.
友達は　パズルだけ…。
あっ。
You said puzzles are our only friends.
けれど　カイトは　パズルを船として
旅立ち　仲間と出会い→
But because of puzzles you set out on a journey,
met new people, and became friends with the world.
世界と友達になった。
よし！　できた！
Okay! I'm done!
いいパズルだ。
えへっ。
That's a good puzzle.
ここが　カイトの住む町。
This is Kaito's town.
清潔で　明るくて　幸福で…
仲間がいて…　みんな笑顔で…。
It's clean, bright, and happy.
You have friends here.
And everyone's smiling.
俺だけじゃねえよ。
その気になりゃ　お前だって。
It's not just me! If you wanted to, you could—
あっ。
なんだよ！　こんな時に。
Dammit, what is it now?
Yesterday
Ito Nonoha:
No subject
Mailbox
Inbox
Sort
Yesterday
Ito Nonoha:
Cubic:
Kaito~~!
Kaito! Kaito!
Cubic:
Something
terrific!
Yesterday
Ito Nonoha:
No subject
Inbox
From: Ito Nonoha
To: Kaito
No subject
Everything all right?
うるせえな　全く…。
Give me a break.
Having lunch. The A set without pickles. Send.
「昼飯中。　Ａセット　ピクルス抜き」。　送信。
井藤ノノハさん…　あの子だね。
Ito Nonoha is that girl, right?
カイトの事　心配してるんだ…。
She's worried about you.
本当に幸せだね　カイトは。
You're really a lucky guy, Kaito.
ルークの　あの笑顔…。
心の声
Rook's smile...
昔のまんまじゃねえか。
is the same as back then.
なのに…　なんで
心の声
滅亡の未来を…　ルーク…。
Then what about this apocalypse?
Rook...
（ビショップ）私は信じていました。
I believed in him.
ルーク様こそが　未来のＰＯＧを担う
お方だと…。
I believed that Sir Rook would have led the POG to the future.
（バロン）しかし　今や　管理官は
かつての管理官ではない…。
But the Chief is no longer the Chief you knew.
分からないのです。　ルーク様がどこへ
行こうとされているのか　私には。
I cannot understand where he is heading.
管理官は　かつての親友　大門カイトに
変わらぬ友情を抱き→
The Chief still holds the emotion of friendship for Daimon Kaito,
彼の心を求めている。
and he is seeking his heart.
（ルーク）あの日　カイトは　僕にとって
永遠となった…。
On that day, you became my eternity.
「カイトが死んだ」。
そう聞かされた日に…。
The day they told me you died.
もちろん　カイトが生きてると
分かったときは　うれしかったよ。
Of course, I was happy when I learned you were alive.
でも同時に　僕は１つの
壮大なパズルを計画した。
But at the time, I was working on a grand puzzle.
カイトを二度と失うことのない
永遠の存在にするパズルを…。
A puzzle that would give you an eternal existence so I wouldn't have to lose you again.
パズル？！　今日までのことは
お前の作ったパズルだってのか？
A puzzle? Until today, you were making this puzzle?
カイトも僕も　パズルの中。
でも　あと少しで　パズルは解ける。
We're both in a puzzle. But it'll be solved soon.
間違ったパズルに　答えはねえ。
間違ってなんか　いないよ。
A wrong puzzle has no solutions.
It's not wrong.
作ったのは　僕。　だから　出口には
必ず　僕の望む未来が待っている。
I made it, so at the end, the future I want is waiting.
探し物は見つかった？
あっ　ああ。
Have you found what you were looking for?
Yeah.
これは…　あの草原…。
This is the field...
√学園に来たばっかの頃
なかなか　なじめなくてさ。
When I first came to Root Academy, I couldn't really fit in.
しょっちゅう　ここに来て
この写真　見てた。
I came here all the time to look at this picture.
楽しかったよな　あの頃は…。
It was fun back then.
ジンと　お前と　３人で…。
Together with you and Jin.
I'm making a new wood block puzzle.
（ルーク）僕ね　今
回想
新しい組木パズル　作ってるんだ。
完成したら　カイトにあげる。
え～っ？！　ホント？！
I'll give it to you when I'm done.
Really?
そしたら　その組木パズルと
回想
一緒に　いつも持ってて。
Yeah. Then you can have it with you all the time!
And when you look at the puzzle, you can remember me!
パズル見るたびに
回想
僕のこと思い出してよ。
うん！　ありがとう　ルーク！
Okay! Thanks, Rook!
回想　いつまでも一緒　約束だよ！
うん！
We'll be together forever. It's a promise.
一緒に戻ろうぜ　ルーク。　あの頃へ。
Let's go back together, Rook.
To that time.
いや　戻してみせる。
それが　俺の解くべきパズルだ。
I'll make it so. That's my puzzle to solve.
カイトの人生も　僕のパズルに
組み込まれている。
Your life is surrounded by my puzzle.
逃げることはできない。
うっ。
You can't run away.
ありがとう。
今日は本当に楽しかったよ。
Thanks. Today was really... fun.
カイト。　もう一つ　僕の最後の願いを
かなえてほしい。
うっ。
Kaito, I'd like you to do just one more thing for me.
（バロン）何ですって？！
それは　本当ですか？！
What? Is that true?
（ビショップ）ええ　それが何か？
Yes. Is something the matter?
Even after losing the Armband of Orpheus, he pushed his brain beyond its limits with his own strength.
オルペウスの腕輪を失っても　自らの
力で　脳を究極まで活性化させた。
信じられない。　そのような成長の
形が…。　一体　カイト君に　何が？！
It's unbelievable. Such an advancement...
What happened to Kaito?
これから　何が
起ころうとしているのか？！
What will happen to him now?
管理官は　どちらに？
はい。　朝から　１人で　お出かけに。
Where is the Chief?
He left in the morning alone.
なんだよ。　最後の願いってのは？
And what is this "one more thing"?
僕と戦ってほしい…　命をかけて。
I want you to fight me.
With our lives on the line.
何だと？！　ふざけんな！
What?
Like hell I will!
なんで　俺とお前が　命をかけて
戦わなきゃいけねえんだよ？！
Why would we have to fight to the death?!
僕たちが　永遠になるため…。
For us to become eternal.
僕が勝ち　カイトが死ねば
僕の中で　カイトは永遠となり→
If I win and you die, you'll become eternal in me.
If I die, I'll become eternal in you.
僕が死ねば　カイトの中で
僕は永遠となる。
Either way, we will stay eternal.
どちらにせよ　僕は
「永遠の僕たち」を手に入れられる。
それが　僕の作ったパズルの答え。
That's the solution to my puzzle!
ルーク…　何　言ってんだ？　お前…。
What are you saying?
君は断れない。　なぜなら…。
You can't refuse. Because...
What's that?
それは…。
神の書…。
あぁ！
The Divine Revelations.
うそだ！　でたらめだ！　神の書は
神のパズルを解かなきゃ　手に…。
You're lying! It's a bluff!
You have to solve the Divine Puzzle to...
The Divine Puzzle that the ancient sage Pythagoras created to seal the Divine Revelations
古代の賢者ピタゴラスが　神の書を
封印した神のパズル。
２人のファイ・ブレインが　命をかけて
戦わなければ　決して解けない。
can only be solved by two Phi Brains fighting.
まさか…。
そう。　ジンとピタゴラス伯爵の戦い…→
No way...
Yes. When Jin and Count Pythagoras fought,
あの時に　神のパズルは解放され→
the Divine Puzzle was released and humankind received the Divine Revelations.
神の書も　人類に
もたらされていたのさ。
一体　神の書に　どんな力が？！
ピタゴラス伯爵は　中を見た。
What power does it have?
The Count saw the contents.
そして　その大いなる神秘と
魔性の光彩に取りつかれ→
But he was possessed by the otherworldly light of the great secret,
寝食を忘れて　解読に没頭した。
and he immersed himself into deciphering it, even forgetting to eat or sleep.
But he couldn't finish and died without gaining the ultimate power.
でも　ついに解くことができず
究極の力も得ないまま　死んだ。
神の書の中身など
僕には　どうでもいい…。
I couldn't care less about the contents of the Revelations.
I don't need anything but our eternity.
僕はもう　「永遠の僕たち」以外は
何も要らない…。
神の書も　未来も
ジンと３人で過ごした思い出も…。
The Divine Puzzle, the future, the time we spent together with Jin...
いや　ジンさえも…。
Even Jin himself...
（ルーク）みんな　僕から
カイトを奪おうとする。
It's all trying to take you away from me.
僕は…　彼らを許さない！
I won't allow that!
神の書の実在を明かせば
必ず　奪い合いが起こる。
If the existence of the Divine Revelations is unveiled, there will be strife.
その究極の力を欲する
権力者たちは　理性を失い→
The leaders wishing for that ultimate power will lose all reason, arm themselves,
銃を持ち　そして　破壊と
殺りくの果てに　世界は滅びる。
and when the destruction and slaughter is over, the world will end.
戦いを拒むなら　僕は抹殺する！
If you refuse to fight me, I'll slaughter them all.
街を！　ジンを！　君の仲間を！
世界の全てを！
This city! Jin! Your friends! The whole world!
So that's how it is.
そういうことかよ！
戦え　カイト。
世界の未来をかけて。　この僕と！
Fight, Kaito! Fight me for the future!
させねえ…。
あっ。
I won't let you.
世界は俺が守る。
お前を　あの世界には行かせねえ。
I'll protect the world.
I won't let you get to that world.
俺が作りかえてやる！
お前のパズルを　力ずくで！
I'll change it. I'll change your puzzle by force!
ああ　カイト！
Kaito!
おお！　悪いな　呼び出して。
ううん。　それで　どうだった？
Sorry for calling you out like this.
How did it go? Did he agree to not fight?
ルーク君　「もう戦わない」って
言ってくれた？
言ったよね。　カイトは親友だもん。
分かってくれたよね？
He did, right?
You're his best friend!
He understood, right?
持ってきたか　ノノハスイーツ。
あっ　う　うん。
Did you bring your Nonoha sweets?
Yeah.
無理すりゃ　食えるな。
つ～か　うまいわ！
I can eat them if I try really hard. Wait, these are good!
なんだ　うまかったのか！
ハハハハッ。
They were good after all!
ありがとう　ノノハ。　元気でな。
Thanks, Nonoha. Take care.
えっ？！　カイト！　あっ。　うっ！
Kaito?!
ああっ。　待って　カイト！
行かないで！
Wait, Kaito! Don't go!
置いてきぼりにしないって
約束したじゃない！
You promised you wouldn't leave me behind!
私も連れてけ！　連れてけってば！
Take me with you! Take me!
このウソつきの　パズルバカ～！
You liar... Puzzle freak!
Jin, I've come for you.
ジン　迎えにきた。
２人で見届けよう…　カイトを。
Let's watch Kaito together.
（ＰＯＧ職員）何をしている？！
貴様！　どうやって　ここに？！
What are you doing?!
How did you get in here?!
（ギャモン）こうやって。
あっ…　ギャモン君？！
Like this!
Gammon!
行こうか　学園長！
Shall we go, Principal?
カイト！
Kaito!
これは　ＰＯＧの…。
That's a POG aircraft...
It's you!
あなたは…？！
Sir Rook and Daimon Kaito are about to challenge the Divine Puzzle.
（ビショップ）ルーク様と大門カイトが
神のパズルに挑もうとしています。
何ですって？！
何としても　食い止めなければ…。
What?!
We must stop them. I'm asking for your help.
力を貸してほしい…。
私も行く。
I'm going too.
あのバカッタレ　タダじゃ
おかないんだから！
I'm gonna beat some sense into that idiot!
（ビショップ）もし　我々の理解すら
超える成長を遂げた大門カイトと→
Daimon Kaito has shown growth beyond our expectations.
ファイ・ブレインであるルーク様が
全力で戦ったらば…。
If he fights Sir Rook, who is a Phi Brain himself...
ピタゴラス伯爵と真方ジンの戦いよりも
凄惨な結末が待っている。
"...the battle will lead to an even more gruesome end than the fight between Count Pythagoras and Jin."
そうですね。
そんな！
Right?
No way!
それで　カイト君は　どこへ？
Where is Kaito?
The island where the Phi Brains have challenged the Divine Puzzle since ancient times:
（ビショップ）太古より　ファイ・ブレインが
神のパズルへ挑んだ島　オルペウス島。
Orpheus Island.
（ルーク）神ならば　それができる…。
でも　教えてほしい。
God can do it. But tell me...
１人の人間が　どうすれば
細い竪琴をよすがに→
How can a human reach Him by relying on a fragile harp?
彼に付き従えるのかを…。
２つの心の道が交差する地に
アポロンの神殿はない…。
At the point where the paths of two hearts cross, there is no shrine of Apollon.
歌は存在だ。
神には造作もないことだ…。
Songs are existence.
For God, it's simple.
でも　僕らは　いつ存在している？
But when do we exist?
そして　いつになったら　神は…。
And when will God...
うふっ。
うっ。
tsukue no ue de umareta sekai
This world born on my table.
ichiban saki ni kimi ni misetakatta
I wanted you to see it first.
karappo no heya sotto nukedashite hashiri hajimeteta
I sneaked out of the empty room and started to run.
iki hazamasete oka wo noboru to
As I got to the top of the hill, out of breath,
kimi ga saki ni tsuite matteita ne
you were already there waiting for me.
takusan no hajimete kimi to mitsuketa takaramono datta
It was the first of many treasures we would find together.
kanashisa de afureta toki wa
When sorrow was overflowing in me,
nanimo iwazu ni tada soba ni ite kureta ne
you just silently stayed by my side.
ima de mo wasurenai yo
I still haven't forgotten that.
mata aou ne yakusoku wo shiyou
Let's promise we'll meet again.
kie wa shinai ano hi no sayonara
The goodbye of that day we'll never forget.
boku no subete kimi ga kureta michi
All I have I got from you,
zutto kokoro no naka hikaru yo
and it will all shine in my heart forever.